Daniele Mingolla

Graduating in Computer Science at the University of Perugia

Excellent problem solving and team working skills developed thanks to the experience as an online reseller and promoter. I am currently engaged in the study of cloud technologies and the main algorithms of Machine Learning.



danielemingollabusiness@gmail.com

+ 39 3468889459

Milan, Italy

17 March, 1998 🎬

www.danielemingolla.site 📾

linkedin.com/in/daniele-mingolla in

github.com/danielemingolla 🦪

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Perugia

09/2017 - 07/2020

DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

IISS "PACINOTTI-FERMI"

09/2012 - 07/2017

CERTIFICATIONS & COURSES

Junior Microsoft Cloud System and Network Engineer

eForHum

02/2020 - 05/2020

System training on Microsoft Cloud technologies and on-premises Windows networking on Cisco Systems technology. In parallel to the theoretical study of the various topics listed below, many consolidation workshops have been carried out. Specifically, the GoDeploy platform was used for the Windows Server and Microsoft Azure laboratories, while for the Networking part, the Cisco Packet Tracer software was used.

Course topics.

- Deploying and Managing Windows Server, Managing Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, IPv6, Local Storage, Group Policy, Server Virtualization con Hyper-V.
- Ethernet, Network Layer, IP Addressing, Routing Concepts, Dynamic Routing, VLANs, NAT (IPv4).
- Azure Administration, Virtual Machines, Azure Storage, Virtual Networking, Intersite Connectivity, Monitoring, Network Traffic Management, Azure Active Directory, Securing Identities, Governance e Compliance, Data Services.

CCNA Routing and Switching IISS "PACINOTTI-FERMI"

09/2016 - 07/2017

Taranto

Course topics:

- Network fundamentals.
- IP connectivity.
- Security fundamentals.

Trinity College London - GRADE 7Edinburgh Language Academy

09/2015 - 10/2015

Edimburgo, Scozia

SOFT SKILLS

PROBLEM SOLVING

TEAMWORK

TIME MANAGEMENT

NEGOTIATION

PROACTIVITY

PERSONAL PROJECTS

REVIEW CLASSIFIER (02/2020 - Present)

 Neural network able to analyze the text of hotel reviews and classify sentiment.

ARTICLEE (08/2019 - 11/2019)

 Open-source platform that offers users the possibility to write and share their articles with the community.

INVESTMENT STRATEGY (02/2019 – 03/2020)

 The strategy is based on capital diversification through investment in 7 different passively managed funds.

WORK EXPERIENCES

PRIVATE SELLER ON EBAY (09/2018 - 12/2018)

The activity included the analysis of the market and competition for the choice of products to sell through our page on Ebay. Once identified the product, we proceeded to the choice of suppliers based on parameters such as shipping speed and quality of the product supplied. The last phase involved the creation of the graphics to be included in the product description and to be advertised on the main social networks.

PROMOTER (04/2018 - 05/2018)

The activity as promoter at Sintesi Promotions S.r.l involved setting up a stand and presenting the products of the well-known brand "LEFFE" to customers.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

ENGLISH

HOBBIES

ENTREPRENEURSHIP

MARKETING

PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT